Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services and an MBA in Finance. I have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years. I have been a
branch manager at one of the leading companies.
Today, I am presenting to you the
term life insurance plans of the top two leading companies in the industry,
ICICI Prudential's iProtect
Term Plan and HDFC Life
Insurance's Click to Protect Super.
I have compared both these term plans in detail
for you. Especially,
which plan will be cheaper, whose features are better,
I have explained it in detail in terms of premium here
because the rest of the
knowledge is that you will get
more benefit in mode,
you will get more benefit in return of premium or
which company will give you more benefit in smoker, you will get more
benefit in 5 pay, you will get more
benefit in 10 pay
or you will get more benefit in regular pay,
in the same company also.
And if you compare both the companies with each other, then
where can you
get a cheaper policy in premium, so in this video,
I will explain it to you in details.  I am telling you that
if you like my video then you
must
buy term insurance to protect your income. Now let us understand the premium wise plan. First of all
I will
explain the term plan of one company one by one. The
rates of term plan in ICICI Preslover can be more or less.
I am making this quotation at non-smoker rate
and here
I have also kept the premium mode as regular that you have to
pay premium every year, you have to pay premium for 10 years, you have to pay premium for
5 years, you have to pay premium for 10 years
but the insurance cover is of
2 crores instead of 1 crore. In other places I have taken
insurance cover of 1 crore and
I pay premium only after 10 years. And
if I take the feature of return of premium then
what benefits will I get?
In the ICICI product, there is no option of
return of premium in the iProtect Smart Plan
but another ICICI has
a plan called return of premium term
plan and it is listed here. There is no
option of return of premium in the iProtect product.
So now let us see here, there is a
person, here whatever options I have
taken, the insurance cover will last till the age of 85
and you will have to pay the premium.  I have
given different payment options. Let's say a 30
year old person
pays a premium of Rs 2251. He will
pay a premium for 55 years till the age of 85. Then he will get a
premium of Rs 7251.
His insurance of Rs 1 crore will continue till the age of 85.
If the same customer decides that he does
not want to pay premium for 55 years but
wants to pay premium for only 10 years and the policy has a
benefit till the age of 85. Diwali has come, then
you will have to pay a premium of around Rs 0000.
If a customer has a
higher capacity to pay premium or has a higher ability
and does not want to pay premium for a long time and
wants to take an additional policy, then if he
pays premium every year, then the premium will be only Rs
106000. 749. He has to
pay premium every year and
he will get insurance of Rs 1 crore in the policy till the age of 85.
If the same customer decides that
instead of Rs 1 crore, he wants to take a higher insurance cover, he
wants to take an insurance cover of Rs 2 crore but
wants the premium to increase only for 10 years, then
They have to
pay a premium of only Rs 877 for 10 years. By the
age of 85, they will have to pay a production of Rs 2 crore.
And here I have written 'A'
in return of premium because 50 year
policy term return of premium is
not available in term plan. 40 year
policy term is available. Now the thing to notice here is
that if he
pays regular premium then he will have to pay a premium of around Rs 15 lakh
in 55 years. But
if someone does not want to afford a big premium
but wants a high insurance cover, then
he can take regular premium. But if
someone can afford it, then for him if he
increases the premium for only 10 years then he will have to
pay only Rs 6 lakh premium. So, it will be
less premium in comparison to 9 lakh regular and
if he pays premium for 5 years then he will have to pay only Rs 630000
premium and
here he will have to pay Rs 530000. So if you
can pay a premium, can pay a big amount,
then you can go for F Pay where
you  You have to pay the premium only five years and you will get
coverage till the age of 85. Now the
thing to notice is that here you see
that for Rs 60000 you are getting an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore
and for Rs 87000 you are getting an
insurance cover of Rs 2 crore. In both the cases, the
premium has to increase for only 10 years, that is,
your premium has increased by only Rs 7000 here, that is, it has
increased by 45 years, but the insurance cover has
increased by 100%, from Rs 1 crore it has become 2 crore, it has
doubled, but your premium is
not doubling. So if you take a high sum
in ICICI, then you are getting more
benefit because if you
take Rs 2 crore instead of Rs 1 crore, then the premium is
not increasing that much, but your insurance cover is getting
very good protection, so
understand that regular will be good for you. If
you do not want to pay a high premium, then you should make a
regular purchase. If you
can afford a higher premium or more, then
Rs 5 or Rs 10 will be a better option for you and if
your income is high, then the income is good.  So
definitely you should buy high sum, it will be cheaper too
and a good insurance will be useful for you, your
family or to protect your income.
If your age is 35 years
then you will get a regular premium of Rs. 0000.
In 10 pay the premium is Rs. 71000.
In 12 pay it is Rs. 127 and if you are
taking an insurance cover of Rs. 2 crore then only Rs. 1 lakh 4000 will
come. See here, in 1 crore there is
Rs. 71000. Here the premium is Rs. 14000. If
you see for Rs. 40 the premium is Rs. 39000.
In 10 pay the premium is Rs. 90000 and here it will
come for Rs. 60000. So here you
can see at different ages which
plan is more suitable for you, which premium payment mode will be
more suitable for you. ICICI
Prudential Life has its own product Smart
Term Plan. Now let's see ADFC
Life Insurance. Let's see
ADFC Insurance. Click to take your plan.  I have
taken a plan by calling Protect Super and
same as I have explained, here
you will get a policy for Rs. 1000 in regular premium, up
to Rs. 85 for Rs. 1 crore,
you will get it for Rs. 10000
in 10 pay, you will get it for Rs. 10000 in 10000 and if you want to
take insurance of Rs. 2 crore, then you will get it for Rs. 000 for
return premium. Here
also the same thing is that it is not covering up to Rs. 85,
due to this you will not
see the option here. The option of
return of premium is available within the inbuilt feature of Click to Protect Super.
I have not taken any separate plan here.
In Rs. 35 crore, the regular premium is Rs. 9000, in Rs. 10 pay, the
premium is Rs. 73000, in Rs. 130000
and in Rs. 2 crore, the premium is Rs. 1 crore 3 lakh.
Here you should notice that
if the customer's age is Rs. 845 and he
pays regular premium of Rs. 2000
Instead of that, he decides to
pay premium of Rs.20000 for only 10 years and in 5 years the
premium is coming to Rs.21000 and in 10 years
if the premium increases to Rs.2 crore then the
premium is coming to Rs.222000 and if he
purchases a policy with return of premium
because here a term of 40 years
is available i.e. till the age of 85
then he will have to
pay a premium of Rs.8948 in 10 years
but if nothing happens to him and he survives till 85 then
his money which is
more than Rs.135 lakh will be
refunded to him. Now the
thing to notice is that here there
is a non-refundable plan for Rs.121000 and
you have a refundable plan for Rs.138000, that is if the
premium increases only by Rs.177000 then in 10 years you will
pay Rs.170000 extra but  In
comparison to 170000, you are getting a refund of
139000. Consider the investment of 170000 as
extra, but in comparison to 170, you are
also getting a refund of 1314 lakhs. And if you
purchase a policy with return of premium, then it
also provides the feature of RPU. For example, if you are able to
pay premium for 1 year instead of 10 years, then the
insurance cover of 1 crore or 50 lakhs still
works and the sum value is also generated there, so the
RPU feature also gets activated
and here you are
not seeing much difference in the premium, so if
you can afford it and your age
is more and you are going for the 10 pay option, then
definitely check once that if I
go for non-return of premium or for
return of premium, then
which plan can be more beneficial for me,
you can select that too.
[Sangeet]
Now let's come to the point where  I have
made a complete video to compare which one will be better for you between the two.
So, here
you will see that if a 30 year old person is
taking an ICICI policy in regular pay,
then it is available for Rs 27,000 and
HDFC Life Insurance is available for Rs 222, that is, for
30 years, 25 years, 24 years,
26 years, AC will be cheaper for you in regular pay.
Similarly, if you look at it in 10 pay, then
here also ADFC will be
cheaper for you. But if I look at F pay, the
premium of both is almost the same.
Here the price is Rs 106,000, Rs 105,000. So here
also ADFC is a little cheaper. But if we
talk about Rs 2 crore, then here
ICICI's premium will be cheaper for you by around Rs 000
in 10 pay. So, if you are looking at higher premiums, then
ICICI's iProduct Smart will be cheaper for you.
Now if you look at it here, you will see that in 35 years, Rs
30,000 or  It is of 29000 in the age of 40, 39000 or
38000 in the age of 45 or 52000 in the age of 45, so
if you look at the age of 45 or 46, from
35 to around 45, then both are
touch and go, there is not much difference
because in III plan you
also get inbuilt accidental disabilities rider where the premium is waived,
which is inbuilt, in AAC you have to
buy it separately, its premium
is charged separately, so if you look at it according to that feature, then the
premium is touch and go for both,
but if you go to the age above 45, then
here you will see that here at the age of 50,
IIC is giving it for 67000, whereas here
ADAC is giving it for 76, so if your age is
more, 45 and above, then you must
check, you will get cheaper IIC term plan,
if it is less than 45, then you will get
cheaper ADFC  If your age is more than 45 then
IIC is giving you cheaper premium in regular pay. If
you look at 10 pay also, you will see the same thing
that as your age increases,
your IIC term plan will
appear to be getting comparatively cheaper, like at the age of 50,
IIC is giving it for 1.42 lakhs and
ADAC is giving you premium for 1.68 lakhs, so
as your age increases, the
premium of IPru becomes cheaper, whether
you talk in 10 pay or
even in 5 pay, you will see this benefit,
like if you see, at the age of 50, it is
255000, here you get 302000, but
here if I talk about 3500, then
here also the
premium is cheaper by 3000, even here if you talk about
limited pay, the
same is happening in 35 and after that, if we talk about 2 crores,
if you invest in high-paying 2 crores, 3
crores, 5 ...  If you are a NEW customer then
you will see a major difference here,
ICICI is much cheaper than ADFC,
suppose your age is 40 years,
ICICI is giving Rs. 133000, STFC is
taking Rs. 167000, if you are 45 years old then ICICI is
giving Rs. 176000, then you will have to pay Rs. 222000 premium in ADFC,
so now you should also
see that if you are going to buy high sum, then
which company will be cheaper for you,
which company is giving you cheaper in regular pay,
which company is giving you cheaper in limited pay
and if your age is more then
definitely compare once that in return of
premium and non-return of premium, if
you purchase from both or even from the same company
then definitely check, you can get benefit there,
now let us see a comparison, suppose
someone does Juba Kesari, then he consumes
tobacco, you are consuming bidi, cigarette, gurga
mawa, anything as tobacco, then
both  Which company's
plan will be cheaper for you? Suppose I am a 30
year old person, here I have taken an
insurance cover of Rs 1 crore, age is 80,
policy term is 40, whichever is earlier, let's say it is
30 years, that is
till 70, if I talk then the regular premium
of ICICI will be Rs 228000,
for 40 years at smoker rate of Rs 1 crore,
whereas today the premium of ADFC will be Rs 33000, if it is Rs 435
in 35 K then ADFC is taking Rs 47000,
IIC is charging Rs 60000 premium, at
smoker rate in 40 K then ADFC is charging
Rs 66000, if I talk about limited pay,
in 10 K, IIC is giving it for Rs 68000, it is
giving it for Rs 77000,
in 40 K, ICICI is giving it for Rs 134000, whereas
HDFC is giving it for Rs 154000  If you are a
smoker, then you have seen that
according to the premium for you, I will again say that
you will get many more videos about
which company is it, they will show the solvency ratio, they will show you the
history, they will show you the claim
settlement ratio, in many different
features it will seem as if you are going to
buy a company, but if you are not going to buy a company, then
you are looking at the plan for yourself according to the premium, so
which plan will be for you according to the premium, this
video is very important for you,
you can purchase as per your choice,
which will be better for you,
like it is said that Virat Kohli's
form was bad two years ago, it does
not mean that it has gone bad, it is good this year, so
if you see, the claim
settlement ratio of LIC was only 96 two years ago,
but now it has become 98 something, so this
claim settlement ratio also keeps fluctuating,
because of this it is not that any
company will reject your plan, it will reject the claim, this never happens, I am
just telling that  In this, every
company rejects the claim if something
is hidden or something is
not better in the terms and conditions, otherwise no company rejects any
person's term insurance or any
kind of claim, so
you can purchase
which plan is more suitable for you as per your affordability.
Now if we talk
about the comparison and other features, then both the
companies were started in the year 2000, ADAC
company was started on 14 August 2000
and III Life Insurance Company was started in July 2000.
Talking about the AUM of both the companies,
IIC is a potential company of Rs 2 lakh crore, it is
such a big company and
hdfc.com is at 98.6 there, but
if you look at the current situation on their website, then it is telling that
this year their solvency is 99.3%, ICC is
mentioned as per 2022,
at 97.9. Talking about the solvency ratio, both the
companies  The solvency ratio of ICICI Bank is very good. According to
IRD, the solvency ratio
should be 150, which means if you have paid a premium of ₹1
to the company, then at the time of claiming back, the
company should have at least 50. So,
ICICI Bank has
₹1 against your ₹1 and STFC has
kept its solvency ratio at 2009, that is,
₹1. So, the claim is
not different in both the companies because the
solvency ratio of both the companies is very
good. If we talk about
how many policies both the companies have sold till now, how many people have been
covered by insurance, then ICICI Bank has
given life insurance policies to 7.72 crore people and ADAC Bank has
given insurance policies to 6.8 crore people till now. The
good thing is that both the companies have banks and
individual banks too, due to which
you will get better service.
[Music]
hdfcfund.com The policy term is 85 years
minimum.  Sum starts from Rs 50 lakh in both the companies, that is
you will have to take a minimum insurance cover of Rs 50 lakh, there is no maximum
limit, if we talk about the premium
payment term, then both the companies have
given many good healthy options,
suppose if you are
taking an ICICI product plan, then you
can also take a single pay policy, in that
you will get a maximum policy term of 20 years, so there is
also an option of single pay, 5 pay, 7 pay, 10 pay
every year, if you want to make regular payment or
pay till 860, you want to pay till
60, you have to pay premium, if you
want to run the policy till 80, 85 or 100, you
can run it, if we talk about ADAC, then there
is single pay, regular pay and you have to select
any premium payment term for 5 years and above,
so you can do that
you should make premium for 5 years, you can select
any premium payment term 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 15, 20, 22  If you have it, you
can do it,
but it is not like that in ICICI.
In ICICI, you have been given a particular condition that you have to take
only five years, you will not get the option of six years. There is seven, there is
10, then if you want 12, 13, 14,
15, then that option is not available.
But in STFC, such options are also
given. If we talk about the mode of premium payment, then
you can pay the premium annually, you can
pay the premium semi-annually, you can
pay the premium quarterly and
you can also purchase the policy in monthly mode.
Talking about accident insurance cover,
you can take this option as an Age-A Rider in both the companies. Suppose you
want a natural cover of Rs 1 crore or an
accidental cover of Rs 1 crore, then in case of natural death, you will
get Rs 1 crore, in case of accidental death,
you will get Rs 2 crore. So, you can take this Age-A
Rider in both the policies.
Talking about increasing sum insurance,
this option is not available in ICICI, but
this option is available in STFC.
Now let's talk about a good feature whose
name is  WAP Rider Waiver of Premium: So,
in ICICI Protection, there is a waiver of premium
which is inbuilt in case of permanent disability
to the customer.
You do not need to pay a separate premium for that.
Suppose the customer meets with an accident and
becomes disabled, then the
company will pay the remaining premiums and you do not have to
pay. But here you are not getting any amount.
In HDFC, you will
get a waiver of premium rider. If there is a critical
illness or permanent disability, most of the
premiums will be waived. But
you will have to purchase this as a rider separately.
You will have to pay a separate premium for it.
Talking about terminal illness, terminal illness is
available in both the policies. Terminal
illness is that thing where the doctor
gives you in writing that within six months
this patient or this customer is going to die due to this disease, then
you get the entire insurance cover during your lifetime. So, there is
no percentage here that
you will get 50% or 60%.
Whatever your basic sum is, as soon as terminal illness occurs,  If you are
insured, its full amount will be given to you
during your lifetime. Talking about critical illness, it
is available as a rider in both the policies, where you
get the benefit of 34 critical illnesses in ICC and
you can avail the benefit of 19 critical illnesses.
In HDFC Life Insurance, a separate
premium will be charged, you will have to take insurance cover separately.
If you want to cover critical illnesses like
cancer, heart attack, stroke, etc.,
you can cover such major critical illnesses in it. For this, you
can also take separate health insurance, but
there in health insurance, the premium increases with your age,
but here,
once your premium is taken, it gets fixed, so
you can also get this
added to your policy as per your need.
Talking about return of premium, the option of return of
premium is
not available in ICICI under this plan
in iProtect, but the company has
another plan called Return of
Premium Term Planning, by its name
you can purchase it separately there,
you will get 25  You will also get an insurance cover of Rs. 60 lakh,
but yes, the premium is a little
higher because it is a separate plan.
Here, above the STFC click to product,
a separate option is given for
return of premium. You
can select that option. You have to
purchase a policy with return of premium. So now let's
talk about another important feature. The
name of this feature is Smart Exit. It is an excellent
feature. Suppose you have taken a policy in ICICI Prosil, have
taken a minimum insurance cover of Rs. 60 lakh, and the policy term is 40,
45, 50 years, then after 25 years, if you
want to do a smart exit, that is, you can
want to close the policy and take the
entire money, that is, after 25 years, you can withdraw with all your deposited money.
Your insurance cover was running for 25 years,
but after that the policy will be closed, but
you will get a refund of the entire money.
This option is available in HDFC.
You can exit smartly after 30 years.
Talking about life stage protection,
this feature is available in both the policies.  Suppose at the
time of your marriage, if you
want to increase the insurance cover from 50%, you can do so.
On the birth of the first or second child, if you
want to take more insurance cover from 25%, you can take it.
Talking about permanent disabilities cover,
here you do not get any separate benefit in ICICI potential,
suppose if you
become disabled, then you are not going to get Rs 50 lakh or Rs 1 crore.
Yes, if you
If something like this happens to you while paying the premium, then you
get the feature of waiver of premium.
In ADAC, this comes as a separate option
where you have to pay a separate premium.
So if you become disabled there,
suppose you have taken a term and disability rider of Rs 1 crore cover, then 1
% of Rs 1 crore i.e. Rs 1 lakh will keep coming to you every month for the next
10 years. This
option is available if you want to
add 'As a Rider' to your policy by paying an extra premium.
If we talk about spouse cover, then the
option of spouse cover is not available in ICICI, whereas the
option of spouse cover is available in HDFC. This means
that suppose the husband has purchased the policy for Rs 1 crore,
suppose he has taken a policy term of 40 or 45 years,
but after 20-2 years, let us
assume that the husband dies, then the
entire Rs 1 crore will be given to the wife
and till the age of 50, the insurance cover of the wife will
start from there, that is Rs 1 crore.  At 50, that is, up
to 50 lakhs, the wife's insurance will
start from there. The remaining
policy term is now. If the wife also dies, then
₹ lakh will be given to her nominee. So
this is an option,
you will have to select it at the time of taking the policy itself. For this,
you will have to pay an additional premium. Let's talk about the
common feature which
is available in both the policies. Income tax benefit
is available in both the policies through Income Tax in ATC and is
tax free in 1010D. Death benefit will be tax free.
Policy revival period of
5 years has been given to you in both the policies. If for
some reason you are not able to pay the premium on time, then
even after one or two years,
you can revive the policy by paying the entire premium at once.
Grace period:
In this policy, if you are taking the policy in monthly mode, then
you will get 15 days and
if you are taking it in any other mode like
quarterly, semi-annually or yearly mode, then
you will get a grace period of 30 days.  You will get grace, that is, let's say
you purchased the policy on November 4, 2023, then
you had to pay the premium on November 4, 2024, but due to some reason
you could not pay, then
you can pay the premium till December 4, 2024, and even if there is a
death during that grace period, the
insurance cover is
passed on to the family. So, the grace period is of
30 days. You are talking about the free look
period, suppose if you
purchased the policy and the policy bundle arrived at your home, but for
some reason you did not like the policy,
you can go back and get it free looked at the company and get the
entire money back.
If I finally compare both these products,
then both the plans are
excellent. Both the
companies have good solvency ratio, claim
settlement ratio is good, AUM is good,
solvency ratio is excellent. Both the companies have
very good features and
many riders.  There is an accidental rider. Terminal
illness is inbuilt. Waiver of premium
benefits are provided. If you want to take a terminal illness, then
those options are provided.
If you want to exit with the entire amount, then
those options are provided. If
you
want to increase the insurance cover as per your life stage, then
those options are provided.
You also get income tax benefits in this policy and the feature is that
you have to pay a limited premium
till the age of 60. You have to pay a regular premium. If
you want to take the return of premium option,
then those features are also provided to you.
So
you can select any option as per your need. But
some questions for you are that
if I were to surrender both the policies, which one would have a higher
surrender value? If both the policies have a
rider, then whose rider
premium would be cheaper? In both the policies,
if my income is not Rs 5 lakh, then which
company would offer a term plan? What is the criteria for income and education?
If I
want to take a policy in MWP, will I
get this policy? If I am an NRI, can I get this
policy?  Can I
purchase this policy in business insurance, it is
like a keyman policy, can I
purchase this policy in partnership form or
not, then you will get answers to all these questions on
whatsapp2
and if you want more information then I have given you
my
whatsapp-web,
you will also get the comparison of term plans and other plans of other companies first,
Jai
Hind